《少年谢尔顿》前情提要
Previously on Young Sheldon...
-安珀是谁  -我在交往的女生
- Who is Amber? - A girl I'm seeing.
曼蒂知道吗
Does Mandy know?
翻译     最讲义气贝大八   油腻希
是她让我去的
It was actually her idea.
你的约会进行得如何
How was your date?
其实我们分手了
We broke up.
校对     不讲文明赛太公
发生什么了
What happened?
没什么  我就是想来这里
I just wanted to be here.
我们也想你来
That's what we wanted, too.
后期      灰灰是菇凉      时间轴    加森
你还能送我别的生日礼物
There's something else you could do for my birthday.
我两周前才刚生完小孩  不行
I had a baby two weeks ago, no.
总监     贝大八
不是指那个啦
Not that.
那是指什么
Then what?
嫁给我
Marry me.
什么
What?!
什么鬼
What?
-你愿意嫁给...  -我有听到你的问题
- Will you marry... - Yeah, I heard the question.
你为什么要问这个
Why are you asking it?
因为我爱你啊
Well, 'cause I love you.
你有吗
Do ya?
有吧
I think so.
你刚刚还跟另一个女生在约会
You were just on a date with another girl.
对啊  我现在本可以在她家呢
Yeah, and I could be at her place right now,
但我却在你身旁
but instead, I'm here with you.
真是谢谢你的牺牲啊
Oh, well, thank you for your sacrifice.
我一个18岁小伙  你相信我
I'm 18 years old-- believe me,
这绝对是重大牺牲
that's a sacrifice.
这下好了  你满意了吗
Oh, great. Are you happy?
她哭或许是因为她妈妈
Maybe she's crying because her mom
不愿意嫁给她爸爸
don't want to marry her dad.
她在哭也有可能是因为
Or maybe she's crying
她妈妈想勒死她爸爸
'cause her mom wants to strangle her dad.
你来啦  生日男孩
Hey there, birthday boy.
你怎么这么早就回家了
What're you doing home so early?
貌似是回来浪费时间了
Apparently, wasting my time.
你不可以说来就来  说求婚就求婚啊
You cannot just show up here and spring a proposal on me.
你求婚啦
You proposed?
不用担心  不会有下次了
Don't worry. It won't happen again.
婚礼选哪天呢
So, when's the wedding?
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
你在干嘛呢
What are you doing?
爸爸跟我在看《星际旅行》
Dad and I are watching Star Trek.
看来是我独自在看《星际旅行》
I guess I'm watching Star Trek.
想我陪你一起看吗
Want me to watch with you?
当然  我给你前情提要一下
Sure. Let me catch you up.
进取号航行到埃米尼尔七星
The Enterprise is traveling to Eminiar VII
想解决他们与邻星维迪卡之间的战争
to resolve their war with the neighboring Vendikar.
但柯克怀疑双方并不是在真正打仗
But Kirk suspects that instead of having a real war,
埃米尼尔与维迪卡之间
the Eminiaries and the Vendikaries
只是很认真地在打计算机模拟战争
are having a computer-simulated conflict.
柯克认为
In Kirk's opinion,
这么做反而减弱了对战争的恐惧
by keeping the horrors of war at arm's length,
使得战争绵延不绝
they're simply prolonging it.
我问你个问题
Let me ask you something.
我就是解答达人  你问吧
Answers are my thing. Go for it.
你真的相信这些宇宙外星人之类的东西吗
Do you really believe in all this space alien stuff?
这只是很简单的概率问题啊
Well, it's simple probability theory.
在我们这个星系里就有上千亿颗星球
There are over a hundred billion stars in our galaxy.
有个几颗能支持生命存在的星球几率不小吧
So it's likely that a few of them could support life,
甚至可能是有科技的文明
or even technological civilization.
耶稣也为了它们的罪而死吗
And did Jesus die for their sins as well?
你有你相信的故事  我也有我的
You have your stories, I have mine.
小乔治好像到家了
Whew. Sounds like Georgie's home.
乔治  醒醒
George, wake up.
好好陪你儿子看《星际旅行》
Watch Star Trek with your son.
演到哪了
What's happening?
进取号航行到埃米尼尔七星
Well, the Enterprise is traveling to Eminiar VII
想解决他们与邻星维迪卡之间的战争
to resolve their war with the neighboring Vendikar.
但柯克怀疑双方并不是在真正打仗
However, Kirk suspects that instead of fighting a real war,
埃米尼尔与维迪卡之间
the Eminiaries and the Vendikaries
只是很认真地在打计算机模拟战争
are fighting a computer-simulated conflict.
-不许睡  醒醒  -我醒着呢
- Uh-uh. Stay awake. - I'm awake.
-小乔治  -干嘛
- Georgie? - what?
我就想来祝你生日快乐
I just want to wish you a happy birthday.
谢谢啊
Thanks.
你没事吧
Everything okay?
我不想聊
I don't want to talk about it.
你跟安珀吵架了吗
You and Amber have a fight?
我们分手了
We broke up.
怎么会
Oh, no.
心疼你
I'm sorry.
或许也不是坏事  你与曼蒂还有丝丝
Maybe it's a good thing because you and Mandy and CeeCee
是个多么有爱的小家庭啊
make such a cute little family.
告诉你  我有注意到她看你的眼神
You know, I see the way she's been looking at you.
-别说了  -我是说真的
- Stop. - I mean it.
我觉得她已经准备好再给你一次机会
I think she's ready to give you another chance.
是啊  或许我应该向她求婚
Yeah, maybe I should just ask her to marry me.
这个嘛...
Well...
但也不要唐突佳人吧
you don't want to scare her off.
你醒很早啊
You're up early.
小乔治通常早上会过来喂她
Georgie usually comes over and feeds her in the morning.
但他好像在生我气
But I think he's mad at me.
是啊  当你拒绝男人的求婚
Yeah, you reject a guy's marriage proposal,
他们很容易走心
they tend to take it personal.
你这是经验之谈吗
You speaking from experience?
老娘当年也让不少人心碎过
I've broken a couple of hearts in my day.
他太突然  我只是有一点吓到
He just caught me off guard. That's all.
现在你有时间好好想了  你怎么觉得
And now that you've had time, what do you think?
为什么只能这么极端
Why does it have to be all or nothing?
我能理解他不爽我
I get that he's mad at me.
但我没想到他会就这么不来喂自己闺女
I just didn't think he'd stop showing up for his daughter.
让他冷静过后他就会想通
Oh, he'll come around. He just needs to cool off.
我问问看  妈妈
Let me ask. Mom,
我这周六可以去看电影吗
can I go to the movies on Saturday?
当然
Sure.
她答应了
She said yes.
好的  那就这么约啦
Okay, it's a date.
谁啊
Who was that?
布兰妮·珀金斯
Britney Perkins.
她是那个头箍牙套小胖妹吗
She that, uh, chunky one with the headgear?
不是  她是啦啦队的  而且还有一口好牙
No, she's a cheerleader and her teeth are beautiful.
然后她...  约你出去吗
And... and she asked you out.
你对布兰妮·珀金斯有何认识
What do you know about Britney Perkins?
这个就是她
That's her right there.
她很可爱
She's cute.
这还是她长胸之前呢
And this was before her boobs came in.
所以她在耍比利
So, she's just messing with Billy?
她也有可能是真的约他啊
She might've asked him out.
好啦  她在耍他
Okay, she's messing with him.
你跟这个女生是朋友吗
You friends with this girl?
我倒想呢  她可超受欢迎
I wish. She is so popular.
有一次她说喜欢我穿的那件衣服
One time she said she liked my outfit--
我穿了整整一周
I wore it for a week.
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
你可以跟比利说他还太小  不可以约会
You could tell Billy he's too young to date.
这招好
That's good.
你很可能是你家最酷的那个人
You might be the coolest person in this house.
未免太容易  但还是谢谢
Low bar, but thanks.
林克莱特博士  我需要跟你谈谈
Dr. Linkletter, I need to talk to you.
我们在我办公室了吗
Are we in my office?
不在
No.
那现在就不是我的办公时间
Then these are not my office hours.
你是利用我对时间表的尊重来治我吗
Are you using my love of schedules against me?
没错
Oh, yes.
高招
Well done.
-林克莱特博士  我需要跟你聊聊  -真棒啊
- Dr. Linkletter, I need to talk to you. - Great.
你有门路让我能进望远镜观测室吗
Do you think you could get me access to the telescope room?
我想寻找能够支持生命存在的星球
I want to search for exoplanets that could support life.
你想家了吗
Are you feeling homesick?
-你是在暗指我来自外星球吗  -没错
- Are you implying that I'm from another planet? - Yes.
我接受你的夸奖
Compliment accepted.
说回望远镜观测室
Now, about the telescope room,
我看《星际旅行》的时候想到...
I was watching Star Trek and it got me thinking...
谢尔顿  尝试寻找
Sheldon, searching for life
其他星球上的生命不是什么正经科学
on other planets isn't serious science.
把这种事留给阴谋论大军干吧
Leave that to the tinfoil hat brigade.
但从统计学角度来看  有那么多恒星与行星
But statistically, given the number of stars and planets,
我们很有希望找到一个能支持生命存在的星球
it's likely we could find one capable of supporting life.
如果真被我们找到  那将会是
And if we did, it would be the greatest
科学史上最伟大的发现
scientific discovery of all time.
如果我也往头上戴水果帽
Yes, and if I had fruit on my head,
我也能成为卡门·米兰达呢
I'd be Carmen Miranda.
我不太懂你这个哏
I'm not familiar with that reference.
以在电影中戴着水果帽歌舞闻名的女星
She sang and danced with fruit on her head.
她为什么头上要戴水果啊
Why would she have fruit on her head?
我哪知道  为防自己肚子饿吧
I don't know, in case she got hungry.
别做梦了  谢尔顿
It's not gonna happen, Sheldon!
你怎么能直接无视一个调查方向
How can you just dismiss a line of inquiry out of hand?
谢尔顿  我有时会为了爽而拒绝人
Sheldon, sometimes I say no just for kicks.
但这次是为了你好而拒绝
This time it's for your own good.
所有追寻小绿人的科学家  都成为了笑柄
Scientists who pursue little green men get laughed at.
我在乎的是科学  而不是我个人名誉
Well, I care about science, not my reputation.
如果你不愿意帮我
And if you're not willing to help me,
那我知道还有谁能帮我
I know someone who is.
我们会被物理学家
We'll be mocked by physicists,
工程师  甚至数学家们嘲笑的
engineers, even mathematicians.
他们不会光说你是个傻逼
And they don't just say you're an idiot--
他们还会证明
they prove it.
如果我头上有水果  我还能变成卡门·米兰达呢
And if I had fruit on my head, I'd be Carmen Miranda.
什么
What?
我也没懂这个哏
I didn't understand it either.
-早  -早
- Hey. - Hi.
-你还好吗  -不好
- Are you okay? - No.
布兰妮·珀金斯约我去看电影
Britney Perkins asked me to go to the movies,
但我妈妈不准我去约会
but my mom says I'm not allowed to date
因为我年纪还太小
because I'm too young.
我相信她只是担心你啦
I'm sure she's just looking out for you.
或许我可以偷溜出门去找她
Maybe I could sneak out and still go with her.
别这么做
Don't do that.
你也偷溜出自己家啊
You sneak out of your house.
我是问题儿童  但你又不是
Because I'm a troubled kid. You're not.
但这是第一次有女生来约我
But this is the first time a girl's ever asked me out.
比利  她并没有喜欢你
Billy, she doesn't like you.
这话什么意思
What do you mean?
她这周六要在家里办派对
She's having a party at her house on Saturday.
她不会去看电影的
She's not going to the movies.
只是在整你罢了
It's a prank.
-别难过  -没关系啦
- I'm sorry. - It's okay.
我可以陪你去看电影啊
I'll go to the movies with you.
你不用这样啦
You don't have to do that.
我愿意啊  会很好玩吧
I want to. It'll be fun.
那你不去她的派对了吗
But aren't you going to her party?
她也没邀请我啊
I wasn't invited.
但这又如何呢  她就是个贱人
Which is fine, 'cause she's a bitch.
你还真是个问题少女呢
Wow. You are troubled.
哈格迈尔校长  我们有个问题
President Hagemeyer, we have a problem.
又怎么了  谢尔顿
What now, Sheldon?
贩卖机里的巧克力饮料不够冰吗
The Yoo-hoos in the vending machine aren't cold enough?
还真的不够冰
Actually, they aren't,
但这件事稍后再说
but we'll table that for later.
我想要使用天文望远镜的许可来搜索系外行星
I need telescope time to search for exoplanets,
林克莱特博士与斯特吉斯博士都拒绝了我
and Dr. Linkletter and Dr. Sturgis have denied my request.
-为什么  -他们说这种研究
- Why? - They said that kind of research
只会给我和学校招致非议
would expose both me and the university to criticism.
怎么可能呢
Well, that's outrageous.
那你允许我使用吗
So, you'll give me access?
当然不行  我也想  但是
Gosh, no. I want to, but...
我只是区区校长
I'm just the president.
使用望远镜必须得到科学顾问的批准
Use of the telescope has to be approved by a science advisor.
真有其事吗
Is that true?
听起来像真事吗
Does it sound true?
-像吧  -那就是真有其事
- I suppose it does. - Then I suppose it is.
我干嘛浪费时间来找你
Why did I even come to you?
所以下次记得别来了
Remember that next time.
提醒一下  她今天要打针
Just a warning, she's gonna get some shots today.
听着  宝宝
Okay, kid.
你不哭  妈妈就不哭
You don't cry, I don't cry.
其实妈妈无论如何都会哭的  但你别哭哦
Actually, I'm gonna cry either way, but you don't cry.
我来了
Hey.
我都不确定你会来
Wasn't sure you were coming.
我这不是来了吗
Well, I'm here.
你就是麦卡利斯特先生吧
You must be Mr. McAllister.
-是她姓麦卡利斯特  我姓库珀  -别闹行吗
- She's McAllister. I'm Cooper. - Can you not?
我只是生怕她误会我们是夫妻啦
Well, I just don't want her to think we're married.
我知道那会让你觉得很丢人
I know how embarrassing that'd be for you.
我没这么说
That is not what I said.
我们没结婚
We're not married.
不关我的事
Really not my business.
说不定与你有关
It might be.
你是儿科医生  他像小孩一样在耍幼稚
You're a pediatrician, he's being a child.
我想我们成为一家人怎么就是耍幼稚了
How does wanting us to be a family make me a child?
你真想在陌生人面前吵架吗
You really want to have this fight in front of a stranger?
已婚人士总是吵个不停啊  不是吗
Married people fight all the time, right?
你不用回答这个问题
Uh... You don't have to answer that.
他们并没有
And no, they don't.
-其实...  -老娘不是叫你别回答吗
- Actually... - I said don't answer.
哈尔迈尔校长愿意力挺我是很好啦
While it was nice to have President Hagemeyer on my side,
但我仍需要顾问的批准才能进行研究
I still needed to find an advisor to approve my research.
一个英勇无畏者
Some intrepid soul who was unafraid of
无惧声誉受损  敢于给予睿智之人
tarnishing their reputation by taking a chance
和未经证实的理论机会
on a brilliant mind and a bold, untested idea.
不
No.
系外行星
Exoplanets?
开什么玩笑
Nah...
没门
No.
-埃文斯博士  我想...  -不行
- Dr. Evans, I have... - No.
经历了八次拒绝  三次捧腹大笑
Eight noes, three belly laughs,
和一位教授假装不会说英语之后
and one professor who pretended not to speak English later,
我终于找到了那个人
I found my man.
打扰了  普拉卡什博士
Excuse me, Dr. Prakash?
-我是谢尔顿·库珀  -是你啊
- I'm Sheldon Cooper. - Of course.
我听说过你很多事
I've heard a lot about you.
但我从没听过你的事
And I've heard nothing about you.
普拉卡什博士  我在寻找一位导师
Dr. Prakash, I'm on the hunt for a mentor
此人要敢于挑战
who's not afraid to challenge
根深蒂固的科学范式
entrenched scientific paradigms.
主流科学确实一直受到
Well, mainstream science has always been
新观点的威胁
threatened by new ideas.
没错  像伽利略就因为
True. Like Galileo being imprisoned
宣传日心说而被监禁
for his heliocentric model of the universe.
那你知道塞麦尔维斯医生
And did you know Semmelweis was put in an asylum
因为建议医生们洗手  就被关进了精神病院吗
for suggesting that doctors wash their hands?
我知道  你知道弥贵尔·塞尔维特医生
I did. Did you know that Michael Servetus
因发现了肺循环而被处以火刑吗
discovered pulmonary circulation and was burned at the stake?
还有亨利·奥尔登伯格被逮捕...
Or Henry Oldenburg was arrested...
他因与其他国家的科学家通信
Arrested as a spy for corresponding with scientists
而被当做间谍逮捕
from other countries!
这不是比赛好吗
This isn't a competition.
我以为我们是在联络感情
Oh, I thought we were bonding.
好吧  我们就是在联络感情
Fair enough. We're bonding.
你有兴趣加入我的开拓性研究
How would you feel about joining me
寻找可能存在生命的
in the groundbreaking search for exoplanets
系外行星吗
that could support life?
我非常乐意
I'd love it.
你想和我一起寻找
How would you feel about joining me
能实现时光倒流的
in finding subatomic particles
亚原子粒子吗
that move backwards in time?
-你是指超光速粒子吗  -是的
- You mean tachyons? - Yes.
说什么胡话呢  赶紧开始我的研究吧
That's nonsense. Let's get started on my thing.
跟你说一声
You should know,
我要用一位更有胆量的导师取代你
I'm replacing you with a more courageous mentor.
我很遗憾  谢尔顿
I'm sorry to hear that, Sheldon.
他不惧怕新观点
One who's not afraid of new ideas.
太好了
Great.
别想成是我离你而去了
Don't think of it as me walking away,
想成是你被抛下就好
think of it as you being left behind.
我不介意
I'm okay with that.
感谢你一路以来对我的帮助
Thank you for helping me on my journey.
但你就像火箭助推器
But you're like a rocket booster
我必须丢弃你
that must be discarded
才能达到逃逸速度
for me to reach escape velocity.
我明白
I understand.
那我走了
I'm walking away now.
再见
Goodbye.
我倒退着走
I'm walking backwards,
这样你的身影就会在我眼前渐渐消失
so it seems like you're fading into obscurity.
很好
Neat.
保重
Take care.
别了
Farewell.
拜拜
Ciao.
旅途愉快
Bon voyage.
回头见
Arrivederci.
多么有魅力的年轻人啊
What a charming young man.
怪咖
Kook.
喂
Hello?
是布兰妮啊  什么事
Oh, hi, Britney. What's up?
周六
Saturday?
其实我...
Well, actually...
我有空  谢谢
I'm totally free, thanks.
你最好了
You're the best.
可能我才是贱人
Maybe I'm the bitch.
你干嘛告诉医生
Why would you tell the doctor
我怀孕的时候你才17岁
I got pregnant when you were 17?
她问我们的交往历史嘛
She asked what our history was.
她是指病史
Medical history!
是她讲话有歧义啊
That was unclear.
糟了
Oh, no.
惨了  我把钥匙反锁在车里了
This is bad. I locked the keys in the car.
-但宝宝在车里啊  -这下你知道惨在哪了吧
- But the baby's in there. - And now you know why it's bad!
死了死了死了  怎么办
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
-不会有事的  -怎么可能没事
- It's gonna be fine. - How is it fine?
别慌  我砸开车窗
It's okay, I'll break the window.
玻璃碎会溅得到处都是
Glass'll go everywhere.
对哦  你真是个好妈妈
Right! See, you are a good mom.
好吧
Okay.
丝丝  没事的哦
CeeCee, it's okay.
我们得保持镇定  别让她看见我们一脸惊恐样
We got to stay calm. Don't let her see us panic.
你说得对  挤出笑容
Right. Happy faces.
宝宝  这种情况很正常哦
Hey, baby, this is normal.
我们都好好的
We're all okay.
我们会把你救出来的
We're gonna get you out.
我们怎么才能把她救出来
How're we gonna get her out?
我不知道啊
I don't know.
对了  我车上有洗衣店的衣架
Wait, I got a bunch of hangers from the laundromat in my car.
我可以用来开锁
I can pick the lock.
快去拿来
Go get them!
谁的妈妈是头号大白痴呀
Who has the dumbest mommy in the world?
你哦  是你哦
You do. Yes, you do.
望远镜究竟在哪
So, where exactly is the telescope?
夏威夷  我们只能访问数据
Hawaii. We just access its data.
我们是要找什么
And what are we looking for?
你要注意这些数字有没有变化
Well, you're looking for these numbers here to change--
变了就表明星星变黯淡了
that would indicate that the star is dimming,
很可能是因为绕其运行的行星刚从前方经过
possibly because an orbiting planet is passing in front of it.
这工作在《星际旅行》里有意思多了
Star Trek made this seem a lot more fun.
我有事想问问你的建议
Can I get some advice?
什么事
Mm. What's up?
我本来和一个朋友约好了  但之后
I made plans with a friend, but then I got the chance
我又得到机会和另一个朋友做更酷的事
to do something way cooler with another friend.
你想放第一个朋友鸽子  和别人出去
So, you want to ditch the first friend for someone else?
也不是放鸽子啦  就是重新安排
Not ditch so much as reschedule.
我想你心里清楚答案是什么
I think you know the answer.
你说得对  谢了老爸
You're right. Thanks, Dad.
我要是知道第二个朋友会约我
And I never would've agreed to the first friend
我肯定不会答应第一个朋友的
if I knew the second friend was gonna call.
我想你心里清楚该怎么做
I think you know what you have to do.
假如这次就是难得的
What if it's one of those times
我必须先犯错再从中吸取教训的机会呢
where I actually have to make the mistake to learn from it?
妈妈  有件事我能问你意见吗
Mom, can I get your opinion on something?
当然可以  宝贝
Of course, sweetie.
我不仅是你妈  也是你的朋友呀
I'm not just your mother, I'm also your friend.
-可恶  -没事  你能行
- Damn it. - It's okay, you got this.
快点
Come on.
快点啊  成功了
Come on... Got it.
太谢谢你了
Oh, thank you!
丝丝宝贝
Hi, CeeCee.
妈妈来了
Mommy's here.
你真勇敢  你好呀
You're such a brave little girl. Hi.
好消息是  她不会留下半分印象和阴影
The good news is she ain't gonna remember any of this.
我们也不用告诉任何人
And we don't have to tell a soul.
拉钩保证
Pinky swear?
好
Done.
趁我们在发誓
And while we're swearing,
顺便也保证以后不再当她的面吵架
let's promise not to fight in front of her anymore.
我保证
Promise.
还有  你下次准备求婚之前
And, uh, the next time you're gonna propose,
稍微提醒我一声
give me a little warning.
-没问题  -好咧
- You got it. - Okay.
曼蒂·麦卡利斯特...
Mandy McAllister...
现在别来
Oh, not now!
比利  我能问你个问题吗
Billy, can I ask you something?
问吧
Yeah.
如果布兰妮邀请你去她的派对
If Britney invited you to her party,
你会去参加  不跟我看电影了吗
would you want go to that instead of the movies with me?
不会
No.
好吧
Right.
等等  我受邀了吗
Wait... did I get invited?
没有
No.
那看来她是邀请你了
Oh. She invited you.
是的
Yeah.
你去吧
You should go.
不行  我们都约好了
No, we have plans.
没关系
That's okay.
我们改天再一起去看电影
We'll go to the movies another time.
如果你希望我妹妹做出高尚的决定
If you're hoping my sister made the noble decision,
你和比利都会大失所望
you and Billy are about to be sorely disappointed...
谢了  比利  你最好了
Thanks, Billy. You're the best.
我听说谢尔顿在跟普拉卡什合作
I heard Sheldon is working with Prakash.
是啊  真同情普拉卡什
Yeah, poor Prakash.
谢尔顿有时真让人受不了
Sheldon can be a bit much sometimes,
但你得承认他聪慧过人
but you have to admit he has a remarkable mind.
他会第一个告诉你他有多聪明
As he will be the first to tell you.
其实我挺想他
I actually miss him.
确实  有他在时
I suppose things are a bit more lively
会更热闹一些
when he's around.
他要是真在其他星球上发现了生命
Wouldn't it be something if he really did find
岂不是震惊世人
life on other planets?
他会立刻成为
He would immediately become
人类史上最著名的科学家
the most famous scientist in the history of mankind.
你去哪
Where are you going?
-去看看他是否需要帮忙  -等等  我跟你一起去
- Just to see if he needs any help. - Wait, I'll come with you.
等等  是变化了吗
Wait, is that something?
没有
No.
那这个呢
What about that?
也不是  这在标准偏差范围内
No, that's within the standard deviation.
是吗
Aha.